STACEY BRANDSMA

staceybrandsma.github.io/
in stacey-brandsma/
staceybrandsma

principal data scientist ~ amgen msc computer science, msc analytics, bsc biology

I am a principal data scientist with several years of experience analyzing data and building and deploying machine learning models in large healthcare and biotech companies, with a passion for analyzing data to improve patient's lives. My area of interest and expertise is at the intersection between precision medicine, public health, and data science and their applications in improving patient care and treatments. I have both a Master of Science in Computer Science and Master of Science in Analytics from Georgia Tech, in addition to my Bachelor of Science in Biology.

Skills

Programming: Python, R, SQL, Bash/Zsh, Git

Methodologies: Machine Learning, Natural Language Processing, Image Analysis, Deep Learning, Big

Data Analytics, Simulation, Bayesian Statistics, Business Analytics

Engineering: AWS, Databricks

Collaboration: Ideation and Project Development, Agile, Code Reviews, Pair Programming, Knowl-

edge Sharing, Technical Presentations, Scrum, Software Testing, Jira, Confluence

Areas of Precision Medicine, Digital Health, BioPharma, Healthcare, Epidemiology, Public

Expertise: Health, Program Management, Research, Biomedical Informatics

Education

05/2024 Master of Science in Computer Science, Georgia Tech, GPA: 4.0.

- Artificial Intelligence, Deep Learning, Big Data for Healthcare, AI Ethics, Bayesian Statistics, Knowledge Based AI, Software Development Process, Human Computer Interaction, Machine Learning and Data Science Tools
- Independent Study: Predictive Modelling for Diabetes, Obesity, and Obstructive Sleep Apnea

05/2020 Master of Science in Analytics, Georgia Tech, GPA: 4.0.

- Machine Learning, Simulation, Data and Visual Analytics, Business Data Analytics, Introduction to Modelling, Introduction to Computing, High Dimensional Data, Regression Analysis
- 01/2018 Micro-Masters in Data, Economics, and Development Policy, MIT.
 - Data Analysis, Economics, Experimental Design, and Policy Analysis

04/2013 Bachelor of Science (Honors) in Biology, Kings University.

- Certificate in International Development Studies
- Elected VP of Students' Association
- Laurence Decore Student Leadership Award from Government of Alberta
- Senior Thesis: Survival of murine norovirus and F-RNA coliphage MS2 on pork during storage and retail display published in International Journal of Food Microbiology

Experience

08/2024-present

Principal Data Scientist, Amgen, United States.

07/2021-08/2024

Senior Data Scientist, *Amgen*, United States.

- Leadership & Strategic Planning:
 - Co-lead of Al Taskforce for Obesity & Weight Management.
 - Co-lead of Al Learning Lab for employees across Amgen.
 - Data Science lead for Al Taskforce for Global Patient Safety.
 - Data Science lead for Rare Disease Targeting using Al.
 - SME for Data Science and Precision Medicine strategy at Amgen, participating in workshops and taskforces to define the future of precision medicine at Amgen.
- Technical Lead:
 - Led the ideation and build process for AI use cases in the obesity pipeline.
 - Author of white paper on AI for Clinical Applications in Healthcare.
 - Tech lead for project to develop competitive intelligence for executives. Built models for news summarization, question/answering, topic modelling, senitiment analysis, and financial forecasting.
 - Helped develop and improve a machine learning pipeline for clinical trial optimization and site selection.
 - Advised business partners on expansion and roll out of production model for Osteoporosis detection.
 - Ingested computer vision pipeline for ingesting cell painting images for cell phenotype changes into Amgen's technical processes.- I led the ideation process to develop use cases for data science in obesity trials and am now building the use cases into proof of concepts.
- Collaboration & Community Building:
 - Vice Chair of organizing committee for annual Data Science Symposium at Amgen, quarterly Al Demo Days, and quarterly Al Tech Talks.
 - Leader and facilitator of Amgen's mentoring program, streamlined and improved matching process using AI
 - Mentor and manager of junior staff and ambassador for data science across Amgen, facilitating symposiums, journal clubs, knowledge sharing sessions, pilots, and lunch and learns.

03/2021-07/2021

Data Scientist 2, Parsyl, United States.

- Built and deployed model for predicting location of health facility using IOT devices.
- Built algorithm for predicting shelf life lost for muscle meat products in the cold chain

04/2020-03/2021

Data Scientist, HCA Healthcare, United States.

- Modelled ICU capacity, COVID-19 hospitalizations, & hospital health status.
- Built end-to-end pipeline for calculating regional COVID-19 R_t values.
- Built and deployed predictive models for cost of hospital visit for a patient.

06/2018-04/2020

Data Science Co-Op, Johnson & Johnson, United States.

- Created product to model anomalous orders for controlled pharmaceuticals, utilized daily by the controlled substance compliance team
- Modelled and predicted promotion timing and efficacy for seasonal consumer products

09/2014-10/2017

Monitoring and Evaluation Officer, Mennonite Central Committee, Zambia.

- Applied statistical procedures for evaluating programs and maintaining indicator statistics
- Managed 17 different projects and corresponding monitoring strategies and evaluations